# Lara S. da Luz **UI** Designer

Able to work in EU

Open to relocate

Open to remote roles

Open to IEFP works/interships

id:8116928

+351 934714040

Coimbra, Portugal

in LinkedIn

Be Portfolio

#### **Hard Skills**

- UI Design
- UX Design
- Graphic Design
- Prototype
- Personas
- Wireframing
- Iconography
- Mock-up
- Brand Design
- User flow
- Illustration

### Soft Skills

- Communication
- Empathetic view on users
- Creative thinking
- Team work
- · Self motivated
- Attention to details
- Organized

#### **Tools**

- Figma
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Adobe After Effects
- Microsoft 365

### **Education**

Oct 2023 - July 2024

**UI Design Program** 

CareerFoundry

Sep 2020 - Sep 2023

Graduation in Graphic Design & Multimedia

University of Coimbra

#### Languages

Portuguese - Native

English - Professional Level

### About Me

As a UI Designer with a background in illustration and graphic design, and experience in iconography, research, and wireframing. I strive for the perfect balance of aesthetics and usability, adding value to your ideas and with empathetic view on users. With my collaboration and communication skills, I am flexible and capable of delivering superior design work.



# **UI/UX Projects**

### GoCamino

UI/UX Design - Project View

Feb 2024 - April 2024 CareerFoundry

A location-based website that helps future pilgrims plan and not get lost in their path with maps and information about all their possibilities.

- Competitive Analysis and Interviews to find the main difficulties around the topic
- Wireframing and Usability Testing to start the design and find the best solutions
- Personas and User Flow to define the main design goals
- Attention to details so the project is consistent

### Down to earth

June 2024 - July 2024

CareerFoundry

UI Design - Project View

A finance management app that provides essential tools to track past expenses, plan future expenses, and manage investments and savings for financial peace.

- Based in the User Stories a personal research on finance applications, created a **User Flow** to guide my design choices
- User testing with the wireframes to analyze main mistakes
- Brand design is minimalistic and delicate, to bring peace and clearness to the user's mind
- Mockups to showcase the final design
- Empathetic view and organization with the complex information within the app

### The Tome

May 2024 - June 2024

UI/UX Design - Project View

CareerFoundry

Most Dungeons & Dragons (D&D) players struggle with creating a character from scratch. The Tome app assists users in creating and managing characters, and is compatible with both iOS and Android platforms.

- Created 3 main usabilities for the app based on my research
- Studied main differences between IOs and Android design rules
- Iconography I designed all the icons of the app
- Prototyped all the process
- Creative thinking around the brand identity

# Experience

tracking system.

### Website for data management

UI Design - Project View

June 2023 - July 2023 Rilix Company

The company needed a website to manage better their orders and replace their old

- Communicated with stakeholders to understand their needs and show my design thinking
- Worked with the developers to proper design accordingly to their capacity

### **ADHD Stories for Children**

Illustration - Project View

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

• Created a concise illustration style to communicate the story with an empathetic view